import questionImage from "../assets/question-bucket-5.svg";
export const questions = {
    bucket_name: "Urbanisation and traffic congestion",
    image: questionImage,
    questions: [{
        question: "Traffic congestion is a problem in Southeast Asia. Of the cities below, which is the most congested?",
        options: ["Jakarta",	"Bangkok",	"Singapore",	"Manila"],
        answer: "Manila",
        followup_text: "Manila is the most congested city among the three options according to a Traffic Index ranking in 2022.",
        source: "https://www.tomtom.com/traffic-index/ranking/"
    },
    {
        question: "True or false: Cars with license plates ending in 1 and 2 are NOT allowed in Metro Manila on Mondays.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "This is part of a Number Coding Scheme by Metro Manila to control vehicle traffic, a huge problem in the city.",
        source: "https://www.moneymax.ph/car-insurance/articles/number-coding-philippines"
    },
    {
        question: "True or false: The longest traffic jam ever happened in Beijing lasted 12 days.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "On August 14, 2010, Beijing witnessed the longest traffic jam in history, extending more than 100 km and lasting 12 days.",
        source: "https://www.arabiaweather.com/en/content/the-longest-traffic-jam-in-history-occurred-in-china-and-lasted-12-days#:~:text=The%20longest%20traffic%20crisis%20in,undisputed%20queen%20of%20traffic%20jams.‚Äù"
    },
    {
        question: "Which Southeast Asia city uses a real-time road pricing system to manage traffic congestion?",
        options: ["Kuala Lumpur", "Singapore", "Ho Chi Minh", "City"],
        answer: "Singapore",
        followup_text: "The Electronic Road Pricing system in Singapore collects real-time adjusted fees from drivers according to traffic conditions.",
        source: "https://www.mot.gov.sg/what-we-do/motoring-road-network-and-infrastructure/Electronic-Road-Pricing"
    },
    {
        question: "True or false: Petrol engines in cars waste about 80% of the energy contained in their fuel.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "The energy efficiency of petrol engines is only around 20%. This means that cars are wasting about 80% of the energy in their fuel.",
        source: "https://sustainability-success.com/environmental-sustainability-fun-facts/#:~:text=This%20doesn%27t%20come%20as,ways%20to%20use%20this%20energy."
    },
    {
        question: "Which Southeast Asian city is literally sinking due to the size of their population?",
        options: ["Jakarta"	, "Bangkok",	"Ho Chi Minh City",	"All of the above"],
        answer: "All of the above",
        followup_text: "Jakarta is sinking slowly into the sea. Ho Chi Minh City and Bangkok are also facing a similar situation, just at a slower rate.",
        source: "https://theaseanpost.com/article/studies-show-jakarta-quickly-sinking"
    },
    {
        question: "True or false: In Jakarta, your license plate number determines which days you can drive.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "This is known as the Odd-even policy, where plates ending with odd numbers are allowed on odd-numbered dates.",
        source: "https://en.tempo.co/read/1719003/police-re-enforce-odd-even-policy-in-jakarta"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a type of public transportation?",
        options: ["Trains",	"Bus",	"Ferry",	"Bicycle"],
        answer: "Bicycle",
        followup_text: "Bicycles are not a form of public transportation. They are NOT meant to transport more than 2 people at a time.",
        source: "https://www.remix.com/blog/top-8-public-transport-examples-for-optimal-city-design"
    },
    {
        question: "True or false: Cars are not allowed on the streets in some parts of Jakarta on Sundays.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "Sunday is a car-free day for main roads in Jakarta. Designated zones are blocked off to motorcycles and cars.",
        source: "https://jakartatravelguide.com/visiting-car-free-day-in-jakarta-2/"
    },
    {
        question: "True or false: Tourists in Bangkok can take boat rides to avoid traffic jams.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "Boat rides along the Chao Phraya River is a way for tourists to avoid traffic jams in Bangkok.",
        source: "https://www.thaizer.com/bangkok-chao-phraya-river-piers-boat-routes/"
    }]
}













